Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
Correct, I have already arranged it
with the committee.
The cargo left from Sasebo Port yesterday,
and is now making its way here
across the Pacific Ocean.
A MIG-55 D transport helicopter!
I'd never have had the chance to fly in one
if it weren't for something like this.
Man, this is what friends are for, right, Shinji?
I figured you'd get claustrophobic looking at
the same mountains day after day,
so I invited you on a date,
since it is a Sunday.
What?! Then today is a real date?
I bought this cap just for today, Miss Misato!
So, where are we headed?
We're taking a little jaunt across the Pacific
on a gorgeous cruise ship.
Wow! Five aircraft carriers and
four battleships! What a fleet!
This really IS what friends are for!
That's your gorgeous cruise ship?
Yeah, she sure is gorgeous!
That's the pride of the U.N.,
the glorious regular carrier
"Over the Rainbow"!
It's huge.
I'm surprised that such a relic is still afloat.
Nah, it's not so bad.
It's a vintage model from before
the Second lmpact.
Give me a break!
Here comes the socket for that kid's toy.
What a child's errand!
Awesome! Awesome!
Awesome! Awesome! Awesome!
This is way too awesome!
Real men shed tears for this kind of thing!
Awesome! Awesome! Awesome!
Awesome! Awesome!
Hey, wait! Wait up!
Damn it!
Stop! Stop already!
Hello, Misato.
How have you been?
Fine. How about you?
You've grown some, haven't you?
Yeah! I'm not just taller,
my figure's filled out as well.
Let me introduce you.
This is the pilot of Evangelion Unit 02,
the Second Child,
Asuka Langley Sohryu.
Episode 8
Asuka
Arrives in Japan
What did you do that for?!
That's the viewing fee.
Quite a bargain, don't you think?
What? Well then, take a look at this!
What the hell are you doing?!
So, which one is the famous Third Child?
Don't tell me that was him.
No, it's him.
Well, he looks kind of dull.
Well, well, I thought you were the leader
of this gang of Boy Scouts,
but it seems I was mistaken.
Thank you for your understanding, Captain.
Oh no, thank you for giving me the
opportunity to baby-sit some kids.
We appreciate your assistance
in the transport of Unit 02.
Here are the specs for the
emergency power supply socket.
In the first place, I haven't heard anything
about activating that toy while at sea.
Why don't you just think of this as
being prepared for an emergency?
That's why the Pacific Fleet is escorting it.
When did the UN Navy
become a cargo service?
It believe it was just after a certain
organization was established.
Quite a grandiose escort for
transporting one single toy!
After all, this is the entire Pacific Fleet.
It's still not enough, considering
the importance of the Eva.
Would you sign this document?
Not yet. Eva Unit 02 and its pilot
have been entrusted to us
by the Third Branch in Germany.
You can't just do as you please!
Then, when will you transfer them to us?
Once we've unloaded in New Yokosuka.
The ocean is our jurisdiction.
You will follow our orders here.
I understand.
However, I should remind you that,
in the case of an emergency,
Nerv's authority overrides yours.
She's cool!
She's practically like Miss Ritsuko.
You're as gallant as ever.
Kaji!
Mr. Kaji, I don't recall inviting you
onto the bridge.
Oh, sorry about that.
Excuse us, then. We're counting on you to
escort us to New Yokosuka as ordered.
This is a date?
Awesome! Too awesome!
Shit! Those kids are really going
to save the Earth?
Times are changing.
I understand that Congress has also
pinned its hopes on that robot.
On that toy? The idiots!
If they've got the money for it,
they should give it to us!
What are you doing here?!
Accompanying her.
I'm on a business trip from Germany.
Man, was I careless.
I should have anticipated this.
Hey! Don't touch me!
I can't help it!
Squadron 3 will sortie as scheduled.
Seeing anyone right now?
And that would be your business WHY?
What? You're kind of cold.
I hear that you're living with Katsuragi?
Yes.
So, does she still toss and turn in bed?
Wha... wha...
What are you saying?!
So, she hasn't changed, has she,
Mister Shinji Ikari?
Well...
Huh? How do you know my name?
Well, of course I do.
You're famous in our business.
The Third Child, who piloted an Eva
in battle with no training.
Oh, no, it was just luck.
Luck is a part of your destiny. It's your talent.
Well, I'll see you later.
See you.
This has got to be a bad joke.
No, a nightmare.
So, what do you think about
Mister Shinji Ikari?
He's boring. That's the great Third Child?
What a disappointment.
Yet his sync ratio was well over 40%
in combat with no training.
No way!
That captain's attitude gets on my nerves.
He's a proud man.
Pride can make you sarcastic.
That Mr. Kaji is pretty lively and funny.
He hasn't changed at all, that jerk.
Hey, Third Child!
Come with me!
So Unit 02 is red? I didn't know that.
The color isn't the only difference.
After all, Units 00 and 01 were created
as part of a development process,
prototype and test type.
The fact that it synchronized with an
untrained pilot like you is proof of that.
But Unit 02 is different.
Created for actual combat conditions,
this is the world's first true Evangelion.
This is the final model!
What was that?
An undersea shock wave!
That explosion was nearby!
What's that?
Could it be an Angel?
That? A real one?
What'll we do? We have to get back
to Miss Misato.
This is my chance!
All ships take evasive action,
but watch the formation!
Where's the status report?
The Cymbeline's gone silent.
Titus Andronicus can't locate the target!
Damn it! What in the hell is going on here?!
Hello, Nerv calling.
Interested in info on the unknown enemy
and the appropriate countermeasures?
This is a combat situation!
No non-essential personnel allowed!
This is just my opinion, but I'd say
this must be an Angel attack.
All ships, fire at will!
Roger.
It's pointless.
So an AT field can't be penetrated
with this kind of firepower.
But why is an Angel here?
Could it be after Unit 02?
Hey, where are we going?
Just wait here a second.
What's going on?
Don't peep, you pervert!
Sorry!
Why are all boys such perverted jerks?
Here we go, Asuka.
Why won't it sink?!
I knew it. Only an Eva can beat it!
Come on, let's go.
You're coming with me!
Hey, why'd we change into these plug suits?
What are you, stupid?
What else? We're going to beat it
with my Unit 02!
No way! Do you have permission
from Miss Misato?
I can get permission after I've beaten it.
Now, I'll show you how magnificent
my piloting is, up close and personal!
Just don't disturb me.
This is odd. It almost seems to be
looking for something.
For an Angel to attack here...
Isn't it a little different from the deal we had?
This is what Unit 02 is for,
and I've generously provided
a second pilot as a reserve.
If worse comes to worst, escape by yourself.
I know.
LCL Füllung.
Anfang der Bewegung.
Anfang des Nervenanschlusses.
Auslösung von Linkskleigung.
Synchro-start.
Program error? What happened?
Thought noise! I told you not to disturb me.
What do you mean?
You're thinking in Japanese, aren't you?
Think in German.
Oh, okay. Baumkuchen...
Idiot! Just forget it.
Switch the base language to Japanese.
Evangelion Unit 02, activate.
Telex from the Othello! Unit 02 is in
the process of activation.
What the...
Nice going, Asuka!
No! Abort the activation sequence!
Reset it!
Don't worry about him, Asuka! Just launch!
What are you saying?!
You can't just violate my command authority
over the Eva and its pilot!
What are you talking about?
This is an emergency!
Who gives a damn about your procedures?
Are you really serious?
Unit 02 is still using type B equipment!
Wouldn't it be bad if we fell in the sea?
So we don't fall in.
Shinji, are you in there too?
Yes.
Two kids!
Good chance to test it...
Asuka, launch!
It's coming!
Here we go!
Where is it?
That way!
We've only got 58 seconds left!
I know that! Misato!
Get the external power supply onto the deck.
Understood.
What is she going to do?
Okay, we're going to jump!
Jump?
Run!
The reserve power supply is in place!
Reactor connection completed!
Evacuate the flight deck!
The deck is ready for Eva landing!
All hands, prepare for impact!
I can't believe this!
Eva 02, landing on deck!
What a waste!
Target is approaching rapidly!
It's coming! Port, 9 o'clock!
Switching to external power!
Switch completed.
But we don't have any weapons.
The prog knife will be more than enough.
It's pretty big.
That's what I figured!
What are they going to do?!
Hand-to-hand combat is the best way
to defeat Angels.
Good work stopping it, Asuka!
That's not funny! The flight deck is a mess!
Hey, they fell!
Asuka!
It's impossible to fight underwater
with the type-B equipment!
You never know unless you try!
What a waste!
How much cable is left?
Another 1,200 meters!
What are you going to do?
We'll manage somehow.
I've got to do something.
The cable's going to run out!
Brace for the shock!
Shoot!
Eva lost the target!
Now's the time to change disks...
A Yak 38 Custom!
Hey, Katsuragi!
Kaji!
I've got something to deliver,
so I'll be taking off now.
Launch!
Take care of the rest of this,
Captain Katsuragi.
He ran away.
The target is approaching Eva again!
It's coming again!
I'll finish it off this time.
What?! It's not working!
That's because this is B-type equipment.
What're you going to do?!
What am I supposed to do?
You're pretty pitiful for being the Third Child!
Here it comes!
A mouth?!
Well, it is an Angel.
Eva 02 has entered the target's body.
Doesn't that mean they've been eaten?
It's practically like we're fishing!
Fishing? Yes, fishing!
We're right back in a pinch now.
Shut up!
Hey, get off me already, you pervert!
But we've got to free ourselves somehow.
Asuka, do you read me?
Don't let go, no matter what!
Captain...
What?
I'm requesting your cooperation.
A point-blank assault by two
of the surviving battleships?!
Correct.
We'll scuttle two of the evacuated battleships
along the umbilical cable and set a trap.
During that time, Eva 02 will open
the target's mouth,
both ships will rush in,
fire all of their bow turret cannons,
and then self-destruct, destroying the target.
That's absurd!
Absurd, perhaps, but I don't think
it's impossible.
I understand.
All hands, abandon ship!
Repeat, all hands, abandon ship!
All frigates, hurry and rescue the lifeboats!
But what about the Eva?
Not to worry. They'll be fine.
Hey! Don't use Unit 02
without my permission!
Do the two of you understand the operation?
I'll do my best.
I'm counting on you.
Both ships have opened the Kingston valve!
Scuttling towards point Z.
Roger!
Cable reverse!
Eva has started to surface!
T-minus 70 to contact!
Hey, how long are you going to stay there?
Get off me already!
But we've got to pry open its mouth soon,
or we'll be killed too!
T-minus 60 to contact.
Status on the Angel's mouth?
It's still not open!
Both battleships are sinking
towards the target.
Eva is continuing to surface,
T-minus 50 to contact.
It's not working!
There's no time left!
Target has passed beneath the Tempest!
Speed of ascent increasing!
You're not going to make it! Hurry!
Don't get any strange ideas.
About what?
Anyway, just focus your thoughts.
I know!
T-minus 20 to contact!
T-minus 15 to contact!
Open! Open! Open! Open!
Fire!
New Yokosuka (Old Odawara)
You certainly went all-out.
I should have anticipated
underwater combat.
Oh, how rare. Remorse?
Who cares? We collected valuable data too.
That's true.
Misato...
This really is something special.
They MATCH!
I don't believe this!
They broke their synchronization
ratio records, didn't they?
For only seven seconds.
It must have been due to the danger.
Hey, where's Mr. Kaji?
He ran off. That idiot's got to be back
at headquarters by now!
It was a pretty eventful trip.
Was it caused by this, after all?
It's already restored itself this far.
It's frozen inside dura-bakelite,
but it's still alive.
Without a doubt, this is the keystone of the
Human Instrumentality Project, isn't it?
Correct.
This is the first human being.
Adam.
She may have looked cute,
but she was a real bitch.
Well, we won't have to see her again.
Yeah, though ol' Mister Big Shot
has to see her at work.
Man, I feel sorry for ya.
My name is Asuka Langley Sohryu.
Nice to meet you.
TO BE CONTINUED
PREVIEW
Asuka and Shinji, who are on completely
different wavelengths,
are soundly beaten by an Angel.
Aiming for perfect unison between the two,
Misato comes up with a plan.
Next episode:
"Moment and Heart Together"
I'll give you more fan service next time!
MOMENT AND HEART TOGETHER